Andy Chao

Full Stack Engineer

Stockholm, Sweden

Email: sinceresolution36@gmail.com

Tel: https://t.me/greatblueknight

Skype: live:.cid.f5e58786e46d7b27

Discord: !Andy.C!#9908

I am a full stack software engineer with a specialization in JavaScript and Python for building backend and client applications. I consider myself a fast learner, self-challenger, and problem-solver. I am looking forward to contributing to revolutionizing the industry with my next employer.

Hard Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular, Vue.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, PHP, WordPress

Soft Skills

Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Time Management, Self-learning, Perseverance

Experience

Full Stack Engineer

ResultId, US - Remote January 2022 - Present

Tech Used: React, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, GraphQL Python, PostgreSQL, AWS, A/B testing, TravisCI

- Participated in code review and team design sessions.
- Took part in updating the website using A/B testing, resulting in an 18% increase number of monthly users.
- Architected and built front end applications from scratch using React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS and Storybook.
- Implemented tracking features to record user activities on the website using Mixpanel and GA4.
- Ushered in and implemented a test strategy in Jest and React Testing Library, resulting in test coverage of 97% of all client code.

Full Stack Developer

DraftWise, US - Remote

October 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Tech Used: Django, DRF, Angular, OpenAPI, AWS, Kubernetes, Express.js, Nest.js

- Designed, implemented and integrated GraphQL APIs using Apollo, Nest.js, TypeORM, PostgreSQL.
- Created and maintained the application-level components using React, Tailwind CSS and Storybook.

- Wrote unit tests, integration tests, e2e tests for APIs, React components and the application using Python, Jest, React Testing Library and Cypress.
- Focused team efforts on testing to improve code reliability as measured by increased code coverage and decreased error rate.
- Recommend and implement performance improvements, resulting in a 26% increase of loading speed.

Software Engineer

Exoft, Sweden

September 2017 - May 2020 (2 years and 9 months)

Tech Used: React, Vue.js, Go, Python, gRPC, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL, Django, Enzyme

- Wrote 190 individual tests across 70 test suites to reach 94% code coverage.
- Worked on 3 MVPs while working with young startups and individual clients.
- Developed a real-time chat application for specific company usage using Go, gRPC, and React. It reduced the business time by 10% and much paperwork.
- Implemented enhancements that accelerated search time by 26% using ElasticSearch.
- Accelerated the loading time by 35% for the eCommerce site by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance.

Web Developer

Pentalog, Vietnam

November 2014 - September 2017 (2 years and 11 months)

Tech Used: Angular, PostgreSQL, SASS, Express.js, PHP, CodeIgniter, Laravel, Adobe Photoshop, OpenCV

- Maintained PHP/CodeIgniter based legacy code base and rebuilt using MERN stack.
- Worked on deconstructing complex features into actionable prioritized tasks with estimated timelines.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed using AngularJS.
- Implemented user-facing homepage with JavaScript, React, and Bootstrap CSS, increasing promotion emails sign-up rate by over 5%.
- Reduced code duplication by using front end design pattern and style guide to keep the code DRY.
- Translated wire framed designs into rich, responsive pixel perfect website pages.

Education

The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong- BS in Computer Science

September 2010 - May 2014